Amit Tailor

803-1455 Lawrence Ave West | Toronto | ON M6L 1B1 647-994-9520 | the_amit@live.com https://amit-tailor.netlify.app/ | linkedin.com/in/theamittailor

Summary

Expertise in Web Development, Software Development, Application Development, Programming Languages, Database, Code Management Tooling and Technologies

Skills & Abilities

Programming/Languages/Libraries HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript (ES6+) | React | Node.js | Typescript | Express | ASP.NET | C# | PHP | Ruby on Rails | Java | C/C++ | Python | Bootstrap | jQuery | XML | AJAX | JSON

Database Management PostgreSQL | NoSQL | MySQL | DB2 | SQL Server | PL/SQL | SQLite

IDEs/Editors and Tools Visual Studio Code | PuTTY | VIM | NetBeans | Microsoft Visual Studio | PyCharm | Eclipse | Wamp Server | Apache Tomcat

Operating systems Microsoft Windows | Linux (Ubuntu) | Unix | macOS

Other GitHub | JIRA| SVN | Git | Firebase | Heroku | Netlify | REST API | Photoshop | Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) | UML

Education

Post-Graduate in Cloud Computing for Big Data

Sept 2016 - May 2018

Lambton College, Toronto, ON | GPA: 3.58/4 | Dean's Honour List

Bachelor of Computer Applications

May 2013 - May 2016

Uka Tarsadia University, Gujarat, India | CGPA: 7.73/10 | Class Representative

Experience

Store lead | SSP Canada, Toronto Pearson International Airport, Toronto, ON

Oct 2018 - Mar 2020

- Co-ordinated and managed staff engaged in their duties
- Managed order availability by keeping detailed records of stock inventory in Oracle's MICROS
- Operated and maintained computer system, printer and other devices

Java Developer Trainee | FDM Group, Toronto, ON

Nov 2018 - Jan 2019

- Actively learned all aspects of the tools and technologies
- Implemented a recycle bin functionality to safely delete and restore files/directories in Unix
- Created complex SQL Queries to extract information from the trading platform
- Acquired knowledge in Professional Skills and Finance

Co-Op Software Developer Intern | Logistrics, LSG Inc., Toronto, ON

Feb 2018 - May 2018

- Analyzed, designed, developed, tested successfully deployed solutions using Ruby on Rails
- Implemented front-end design, back-end coding and database management
- Worked with Google Maps, Open Street Map and Bing Maps
- Developed solutions using Ubuntu 16.04 LTS and PuTTY

Cashier and Sandwich Artist | Subway Restaurant, Toronto, ON

Jan 2017 - Jul 2017

- Operated POS system, handled cash and credit card equipment
- Resolved customer complaints, guided them and provided relevant solutions

Project Work

Evento - an Online Event Management System

- Developed in ASP.Net using C#, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, jQuery and SQL Server for database
- Used waterfall methodology and applied SEO practices
- Hand-coded all components, as well as cross-browser development
- Used Microsoft SQL Server for database
- Prepared technical documents such as ER diagram and class diagrams for the project

Amazon Clone - a Fully Functional eCommerce Website

<u>Link</u>

- Developed using ReactJS JavaScript library, HTML5, CSS3 and Node.js
- Used Google Firebase for Authentication, Database, Functions and Hosting
- Utilized Material-UI icons and axios and react-router-dom packages with NPM
- Integrated Stripe payment processing to accept payments online

Netflix Clone - a Trailer on Demand Platform

Link

- Developed using ReactJS JavaScript library, HTML5 and CSS3
- Used OMDb API to obtain the list of movies
- Utilized movie-trailer and YouTube packages with NPM

Tinder Clone <u>Link</u>

- Developed using MERN stack MongoDB, Express, React and Node
- Utilized react-tinder-card package
- · Applied MongoDB to store and retrieve data
- Used Heroku for back-end hosting

LinkedIn Clone Link

- Developed using React-Redux
- Utilized firebase authentication, firestore (real-time database) and hosting
- Applied useState, useEffect and useReducer hooks

Certifications

Responsive Web Design | freeCodeCamp

Issued January 8, 2021

- Completed 300 hours of coursework and 5 responsive web applications in just 10 days
- See credential

Interests and Activities

- Solving coding problems
- Travelling and exploring new places

Languages

Gujarati | Hindi

References

• References available upon request